# GABRIELLE BANIQUED

Fort Washington, MD • ollergabrielle@gmail.com • (301) 751 7970 • gabbley.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

A motivated and team-oriented individual with 1 year of professional experience working remotely in an Agile environment and 5 years of leadership experience in non profit organizations. Proven ability to work across multiple departments and teams within significant time and resource constraints. Seeking opportunities in data analysis, UX/UI research, or software development using Java, Python, SQL.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MENTOR COLLECTIVE, Boston, MA (Remote) Data Analyst Intern Jun 2021-May 2022

- Built live reporting dashboards for Marketing teams to evaluate the performance of their Email and SMS campaigns. Created documentation and internal white papers summarizing the findings. Presented dashboards and findings during a company-wide demo.
- Co-hosted workshop to teach non-technical employees how to use a data visualization tool -Metabase. Created and presented materials for non-technical users. Answered questions and conducted a walkthrough to demo the usage. Documented and updated queries and visualizations to be more user-friendly.
- Demoed applications to key stakeholders, received change requests and created requirements for the updates.

- Wrote SQL queries for a large and fast-growing Postgres database to answer data questions for Product and Research.
- Created dashboards using data visualization tool Metabase, in collaboration with Team Leads and Stakeholders from Marketing, Research, Engineering, Program Support, and Product.
- Used Google Suite as project management and sprint management tool.
- Used Asana to manage sprint boards, retros, reviews, tickets, bug tracking.

## **COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT**

"HOMEBOUND" REGIONAL YOUTH CONFERENCES, Couples for Christ USA National Event Head

Mar 2022-Oct 2022

- Formed a team structure to facilitate mentorship and training of young adult leaders from a national to regional level.
- Proposed a return to in-person youth conferences while prioritizing the health and safety of the youth attendees. Created and presented proposal materials, including detailed COVID safety guidelines and a Gantt chart, to a national committee for approval.
- Mentored and assisted the young adult volunteer leading the Marketing Team by setting requirements for designs, collaborating on graphics, and conducting monthly 1:1 meetings.
- Led biweekly national committee head check-in meetings. Delegated and prioritized tasks. Conducted monthly meetings with

• Hosted meetings for the national committee heads and had regular 2:2 meetings with the committee heads to check in on their tasks. Delegated tasks every meeting (biweekly)

each committee head pair to check in on tasks and address concerns.

"YOUTH COMMUNICATIONS", Couples for Christ Youth USA (CFCYUSA) Media Coordinator

Mar 2017-Aug 2022

- Built, trained, and guided marketing and photo/video teams for annual national youth conferences from 2017-2019. Continued to lead marketing teams as conferences transitioned to virtual and hybrid formats in 2020-2021.
- Collaborated with national leaders to release statements regarding the COVID-19 pandemic and social justice issues as they arose in 2020. Designed graphics to accompany statements and distributed materials on social media platforms and newsletters. Submitted iterations for review and updated as needed.
- Marketed national and regional events and announcements on Facebook, Instagram, YouTube, and through email campaigns.
- Maintained a newsletter on Mailchimp on behalf of CFCYUSA to encourage staying connected during the COVID-19 Pandemic. Managed a team of 4 to ideate, write, and send monthly newsletters.
- Maintained the organization's photo archive of youth ministry national, regional, and local events on Smugmug.

## **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND COLLEGE PARK, College Park, MD Bachelor of Science in Computer Science With a Concentration in Data Science and a Minor in Sustainability Studies

May 2022

#### COURSEWORK AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to Data Science
  - Completed 5 projects aimed to provide hands-on experience with industry-level data science tools such as Pandas, NumPy, SciKit, Folium, Apache Spark, and Jupyter/IPython Notebook.
    - Final Project: Workplace attitudes towards mental health and their impact on employee productivity (*gabbley.github.io/mentalhealth-productivity*)
  - Skills acquired: Data scraping, Data cleaning, Handling missing data, Exploratory Data analysis, Predictive modeling, Trend analysis, Pattern recognition, Regression analysis, Gradient descent using a variety of datasets (small to large, clean to messy).
- Machine Learning
  - Explored models and algorithms used in Supervised Learning (Decision trees, KNN algorithm, Perceptron, Naive Bayes model, Neural networks, Gradient descent) and Unsupervised Learning (K-means, PCA).
- Database Design
  - Gained in-depth knowledge of Relational database concepts and learned to identify good relational database design.
  - Skills acquired: Reducing E-R Diagrams to Relational Schemas, Intermediate SQL (JOIN, CTE, Subqueries, Views, Modifying the database, Functions and procedures).
- Advanced Data Structures
  - Learned the descriptions, properties, and storage allocation functions of data structures (Heaps, Balanced binary trees, B-Trees, Hash tables, Skiplists, Tries, kd-trees, Quadtrees) and algorithms for manipulating structures.
- Design and Analysis of Computer Algorithms

- Introduced to common problems (Network flow, Independent set, Clique decision) and the algorithms used to solve them. Learned to identify whether problems are NP, NP-Complete, or NP-Hard to complete proofs.
- Human-Computer Interaction
  - Designed and built a mobile application based on Task Centered and User Centered design principles using HTML/CSS and Javascript for a semester-long group project. Peer-reviewed the website of another group.
  - o Skills acquired: Perform Heuristic Evaluations, Design User Studies

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Proficient in Java, Python, SQL; Experience with Ruby, Rust, Racket, R, C++, C, OCaml, HTML/CSS, Javascript
- **Data Science Tools:** Pandas, NumPy, SciKit, Folium, Apache Spark, Matlab, Beautiful Soup, Advanced Microsoft Excel (Pivot tables, V-lookup, data validation, charting, visualization)
- Data Exploration and Visualization Tools: Microsoft Excel, Metabase (on AWS Elastic Beanstalk and Heroku)
- **Databases:** PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL
- **Software and Applications:** Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, PyCharm, Docker, VMWare, Android Studio, Jupyter Notebook, Github Desktop, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite, Asana, Slack, Zoom
- **Application Mockup Tools:** Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Canva
- Other Technical Skills: Linux/Unix Scripting, Git, Github, Agile